Guide to the Internation Brotherhood of Teamsters Human Services Department records records, 1963-1996 IBT0032
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Human Services Department records
1963-1996
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
International Brotherhood of Teamsters
IBT0032
1.5 Linear Feet
This collection contains material produced or amassed by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Human Services Department dating between 1963-1996.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Organized into one series: Saul Bronder files.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains material produced or amassed by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Human Services Department dating between 1963-1996.
Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions; Labor; Historians
- Saul Bronder files, 1963-1996; 1985-1988; Series 1; 1 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject folder title.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains material related to efforts by Saul Bronder and other IBT historians' to establish a national IBT archive between the years of 1963 and 1996. Most were produced between 1985 and 1988 during a Bronder's push as IBT research historian for the creation of the archives. Included are memoranda and correspondence, reports, grant proposal and award information, and a collection of labor history resources.
  - Chronology of Labor History, ND; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Harold J. Gibbons Collection, 1987; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Historical Associates, Inc. IBT Archives Plan, 1985-1986; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Human Resources Department Employee Handbook, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - IBT Archives Consultation Grant, 1987-1988; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - IBT Archives Implementation Grant, 1987-1988; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - IBT Archives Proposals, 1976-1982; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - IBT Archives Proposals, 1987-1988; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - International Teamster Magazine Indexing Handbook, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Labor History Resources, 1967-1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda, Correspondence and Reports [1/2], 1986-1988; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda, Correspondence and Reports [2/2], 1986-1988; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Saul Bronder Archives Department Proposal, 1988 September 26; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Society of American Archivists "Starting an Archives" Workshop, 1986 September 12-14; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - State Historical Society of Washington / IBT Local 695 (Madison) Archives, 1963-1996; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    General
    Contains correspondence, reports, and archival finding aids.
  - Teaching Labor Studies in the Schools, Lesson Plans, Volume 1, 1987; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Labor Studies in the Schools, Lesson Plans, Volume 2, 1988; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)